<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on OSDD-1</title>
    <link>https://osdd.one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on OSDD-1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osdd.one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Persecutors</title>
      <link>https://osdd.one/alter/persecutors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 14:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osdd.one/alter/persecutors/</guid>
      <description>Many individuals with DID/OSDD-1 will have alters that demonstrate hostile or seemingly malicious behaviours towards others, whether it be externally to other people or internally towards other alters. These alters are often referred to as Persecutory Alters or Persecutors.
Persecutors are sometimes seen as evil or malignant due to the nature of their behaviours, but it is important to recognise that this is not the case and they are in fact still part of the brain to which they belong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Alters</title>
      <link>https://osdd.one/alter/formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 03:07:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osdd.one/alter/formation/</guid>
      <description>Erdinç Öztürk and Vedat Şar theorise that there&amp;rsquo;s 3 ways alters can form. The first is a traumatic break resulting from estrangement (essentially where the brain isn&amp;rsquo;t able to integrate whatever&amp;rsquo;s happened into an existing part so a new part breaks off) which is what most resembles the traditional &amp;ldquo;split&amp;rdquo; that people discuss in the context of DID/OSDD-1.
The second way is what is discussed as auto reparation, where a copy of a part at a given time, specific to the trauma that has occured, is made and acts as a sort of backup of the autobiographical events, which can later gain autonomy over time and create the basis for a new part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apparently Normal Parts and Emotional Parts</title>
      <link>https://osdd.one/alter/anpep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osdd.one/alter/anpep/</guid>
      <description>In the context of trauma related structural dissociation, there are the Apparently Normal Parts of the personality (ANP) and the Emotional Parts of the personality (EP).
ANP are the parts that may appear normal, at least to some extent, as a result of negative dissociative symptoms. They are dissociated from the traumas that have been experienced and even after being made aware of a trauma, and overcoming any denial, will struggle to perceive it from a first person perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
